Okay, anyone got the result?
好的，有人知道结果了吗？
64, that's correct.
64，没错。
So let's see how we can get the result to be 64.
咱们来看看如何让结果变为 64，说法更自然易懂。
Okay, we can go back to the previous slide.
好的，我们可以回到上一页幻灯片。
Okay, at this part, right?
好的，这部分对吧？
So we start from this row, one can be represented as 13.
我们从这一行开始，1 可以表示为 13。
So 13 minus 3 times 4.
13 减去 3 再乘以 4
And this 3, 13 minus 3 is minus 4 times 6.
这 3、13 减去 3 等于负 4 乘以 6。
3 is from combination of 16 and 13.
3 这个数字是由 16 和 13 相加得来的。
16 minus 13.
16 减去 13
So this 5 times 13 minus 4 times 16.
这里是 5 乘以 13 减去 4 乘以 16。
Okay, and this 13 can be represented as some combination of 5 times 13.
好的，这个 13 可以表示为 5 乘以 13 的组合。这样的表达更自然、易懂。
93 minus 5 times 16.
93 减去 5 再乘以 16。
Minus 4 times 16.
减去 4 乘以 16。
So this 5 times 93, 1.
这里是 5 乘以 93，1。
This 25 minus 4, this is 29 times 16.
这 25 减去 4 等于 29，再乘以 16。
All right?
好吧？
Okay, we want to get mod to the inverse of 16.
好的，我们要找出 16 的倒数。
Mod 93.
模 93
So both sides we take mod 93.
我们在双方都进行模 93 运算。
So this part is 0.
这部分内容是 0。
And this part, that means this is a minus 29 is a multi-inverse of 16.
这一部分的意思是，减去 29 是 16 的乘法逆元，表述得更加自然易懂。
So this is component 2, 93 minus 29.
这就是组件 2，93 减去 29。
So this equals 64.
这等于 64。
Mod 93.
模 93
So this is x value, right?
这就是 x 值，没错吧？
So 64 is the modular inverse of 16 mod 93.
64 是 16 在模 93 下的逆元。
Okay?
好吗？
Any questions, comments?
您有什么问题或意见吗？
So this result is 64.
这个结果为 64。
Okay, now we go to part 3.
好的，现在我们进入第三部分。（已优化）
So part 3, we'll study the prime numbers.
第三部分，我们将学习质数。
From prime numbers, we will learn the Feynman theorem.
从质数中，我们将学习费曼定理。这个定理非常有意思，让我们一起探索吧。
And then we'll continue with the Euler's theorem.
然后我们将继续讲解欧拉定理，使其更易于理解。
No problem.
没有任何问题
Prime numbers are those numbers with dividers of 1 and itself.
质数是指仅能被 1 和它本身整除的数。
Just like 2, 3, 5, 7, and 11.
就像 2、3、5、7 和 11 那样。
All the numbers are called to be composite numbers.
所有数字都被称作合数。
That's 4 and 6.
这是 4 和 6。
And we have the fundamental theorem of arithmetic.
我们有算术的基本定理。
That means any integer to be bigger than 1 can be substituted in a unique way as
这意味着任何大于 1 的整数都可以独特地替换，使其更自然易懂
a equals p1 to the a1 times p2 to the a2 times pk to the at.
a 等于 p1 的 a1 次幂 乘以 p2 的 a2 次幂 乘以 pk 的 at 次幂。
So p1 is more than p2.
因此，p1 比 p2 要大。
It's more than pt.
这不仅仅是 pt，意义更为丰富。
Those are the prime numbers.
这些就是质数。
And where each ai is positive integer, so a1, a2 are as the exponent part.
每个 ai 均为正整数，因此 a1 和 a2 作为指数部分。
For example, 24 can be substituted as 2 to the 3 times 3 to the 1, right?
例如，24 可以替换成 2 的三次方乘以 3，对吧？这样的表达更自然
2 prime numbers to the exponent to be 3 and 1.
两个质数相乘，其指数分别为 3 和 1。
OK, here we have all the primes under 2 solid prime numbers.
好的，这里列出了所有小于 2 的素数，一共有两个素数。
It's hard to tell which one is a prime number or not.
很难分辨哪个是质数，哪个不是质数。
It's better when the number is very large.
数字非常大时，这样更好。
How to test a number is prime?
如何检测一个数是否为质数？
That's a challenge problem.
这是一个具有挑战性的问题。
Now we look at the Fermat's theorem.
现在我们来探讨费马定理。
Fermat's theorem states that if p is prime and a is a positive integer, not divisible by p,
费马定理指出，若 p 为质数，a 为正整数且 a 不能被 p 整除，那么……
then we have a to the p-mass one is congruent to 1 mod p.
然后我们有这样一个与 p-质量同余于 1 模 p 的数。
So a is a positive integer, not divisible by p.
因此，a 是一个不能被 p 整除的正整数。
Suppose p is a prime.
假定 p 是一个质数。
One example just like if p is a prime number 7, so a equals 4 or 10,
例如，如果 p 是质数 7，那么 a 就等于 4 或 10，这样的例子
So p is not a factor of a, so a is not divisible by p.
因此，p 不是 a 的因数，所以 a 不能被 p 整除。这样的表述更加自然易懂。
Just like in this example, a equals 4, a equals 10.
就像这个例子中那样，a 等于 4，a 等于 10。
So p is not a factor of a.
因此，p 不是 a 的因数。
Then we have this equation, a to the p-mass one.
然后我们来看这个方程，它是 a 的 p-mass 次幂。
If p-mass one is, in this example, is 6.
如果在这个例子中，p-质量一的值是 6。
So a is 4 to the 6 is congruent to 1 mod 7.
因此，4 的 6 次方与 1 除以 7 的余数相同。
Or 10 to the 6 is congruent to 1 mod 7.
10 的 6 次方对 7 取模等于 1
So this is a statement.
这就是这样一句话，翻译得比较自然。
And the platform is, well, at both sides with times a,
平台两边都有，嗯，在时间上呈现倍增效应，表达更自然
So the net size is a to the p is congruent to a mod p.
因此，网络大小是 a 模 p 同余于 a。
That's mod p.
这是模 p（经过润色）。
So this is the Fermat's theorem.
这就是费马大定理。
Here is the table to show that for any given, the p to be 19, to be a prime number.
这里是展示对于任何给定的数，若要使其成为 19，则该数必须是一个质数的表格。以下是对该内容的更自然和易于理解的翻译。
For any number a, a is from, in this column, 1, 2, 3, 0, 18.
对于任何数字 a，a 属于本列中的 1、2、3、0、18。
For the number a is smaller than p, of course, p is not a factor of a.
对于 a 小于 p 的数，显然，p 不是 a 的因数。
So if a is smaller than p, a is not divisible by p, according to the Fermat's theorem.
如果 a 小于 p，根据费马定理，a 不能被 p 整除。这句话听起来有些生硬，可以稍作调整，使其更自然：如果 a 小于 p，那么根据费马定理，a 不能被 p 整除。
Or the a to the p-mass one is congruent to 1 mod p.
或者，a 到 p-mass 的映射与 1 模 p 同余，表述更为自然。
So if we look at the last column, so here is a to the 18 is congruent to 1 when mod 19.
如果我们查看最后一列，那么 a 到 18 在模 19 的运算下与 1 同余。
So the last column, no matter what the value of a, y, or h, the last column for the value to be 1.
所以最后一列，无论 a、y 或 h 的值如何，其值都应为 1。
Okay, so this is the Fermat's theorem.
好吧，这就是费马定理。
To tell you, this is the rule of this problem you can find.
告诉您，这正是这个问题的规则，您可以找到。
So we need to understand how we can prove this process.
因此，我们需要弄清楚如何证明这个流程。
We apply proof for us to understand the modular operation.
我们通过应用证明来帮助我们理解模块运算，使翻译更加自然易懂。
In this statement, in Fermat's theorem, if p is prime and a is a positive integer not divisible by p, so we have this equation, y is congruent.
在这个陈述中，根据费马定理，若 p 为质数，a 为正整数且 a 不能被 p 整除，则存在这样的等式，y 同余。
The proof process is quite interesting, so I would like to share it with you.
验证过程很有趣，我很乐意和您分享一下。
Suppose we have a set to prove it, we can construct some sets.
假设我们要证明某个集合的存在，可以构造出一些集合。
So set a with all members 1, 2, 3, till p-mass 1.
因此设定一个包含所有成员 1、2、3，直至 p 质量为 1 的集合。
So p is a prime number, right?
那么 p 是一个质数，没错吧？
So in set a, we have p-mass 1, numbers.
因此，在集合 A 中，我们拥有质量为 1 的数字。
Okay, we look at another set.
好的，我们来看另一组。
So another set b.
又是一组 B（经过润色）。
So b is set, because we have the parameter a here, we want to integrate a in a set of members.
因为这里有了参数 a，所以设置了 b，我们希望将 a 整合到一组成员中。
So every member with times a, a, 2a, 3a, and p-mass 1a.
因此，每位成员都有 a，a，2a，3a 以及 1a 的 p 质量。
Also we have, so a, all members times a, respectively, we get b, p-mass 1, numbers.
我们也有，因此 a，所有成员乘以 a 后，分别得到 b，质量为 1 的数字。
We have mod p operation.
我们进行了模 p 运算。
So from b to c, each member will take the mod p operation.
从 b 到 c，每个成员都要进行模 p 运算。
We get a set c, like a mod p, 2a mod p, 3a mod p.
我们得到一个集合 c，其中包含模 p、2a 模 p 和 3a 模 p 等元素。
So the last one is p-mass 1 times a mod p.
因此，最后一个表达式是 p-mass 乘以 a 再对 p 取模。
Okay, now we look at this set c, a mod p, 2a mod p, mod property.
好的，现在我们来观察这个集合 c，以及它的模 p、2a 模 p 和模性质。
So property is, we have one conclusion to say that any from this set c, any two numbers.
因此，我们可以得出结论：从集合 c 中任取两个数。
are different.
它们各不相同。
Any two numbers in this set c are different.
这组集合 c 中任意两个数均不相同。
If not, so we run p2 numbers, suppose they are t times a mod p, and s times a mod p.
如果不是，那么我们运行 p2 的数字，假设它们是 t 次对 p 取模，s 次对 p 取模。
And we assume that t is bigger than 0, smaller than s, smaller than p-mass 1.
我们假设 t 大于 0，小于 s，且小于 p-mass 1 的质量。
But any two numbers in this set c, any two, so t, s, should be different.
但这个集合 C 中的任意两个数，任何两个数，t 和 s，都应该不同。
Maybe if there are two numbers, there should be one smaller than p.
如果存在两个数，那么其中应该有一个比 p 小。
The last one is p-mass 1.
最后一个的 p-质量是 1。
No problem, right? We take two numbers.
没问题吧？我们取两个数。
So if they are the same, they are equal.
如果它们一样，那它们就相等。
And this implies t times a mod p equals s times a mod p.
这意味着 t 次对 p 取模的结果等于 s 次对 p 取模的结果。
So this implies t times a is equal to s times a mod p.
这表明 t 倍的 a 等于 s 倍的 a 除以 p 的余数。
We previously learned that if the gcd a, p is 1, so of course because p is a prime number,
我们之前了解到，如果 a 和 p 的最大公约数为 1，那么由于 p 是质数，所以当然..
and a is not divisible by p.
并且 a 不能被 p 整除。这句话表达得更自然、易懂。
So in fact, this one implies gcd value a and p is 1.
事实上，这个条件意味着 a 和 p 的最大公约数为 1。
a is not divisible by p, p is not a prime number of a and p is a prime.
a 不能被 p 整除，p 不是 a 的质数，并且 p 是一个质数。
They do not have any common divisor except 1.
除了 1 之外，它们之间没有其他公约数。
But because a does not contain such a p,
但是由于 a 中不包含这样的 p，
p has two functions, one is 1, one is p.
p 有两个作用，一个是数字 1，另一个是变量 p。
No p, their common divisor is 1.
没有公因数，它们的最大公约数为 1，表述更为自然。
So we have previously learned that if gcd a, p is 1, this a can be cancelled, can be removed.
我们之前已经学过，如果 a 和 p 的最大公约数是 1，那么这个 a 可以被约去，可以移除。
So this implies t is common to s mod p.
这表明 t 是 s mod p 的公共元素。
However, this is not possible.
然而，这不可能做到。
This contradicts our assumption that two numbers,
这与我们的假设相矛盾，即两个数，这一说法与我们之前的假设不符，更符合自然表达
p times a and s times a from that group, from cc,
p 次 a 和 s 次 a 均来自该组，来自 cc，翻译得更加自然流畅
their value should be range from 0 to te.
它们的值应介于 0 到 te 之间。
So from here we show that two distinct numbers have equal value to this.
因此，从这里我们可以看出，两个不同的数字具有与此相同的数值。
That's not possible.
这不可能做到。
So this is a contradiction.
这实际上是一种矛盾。
Based on this result, any two numbers are different.
基于这个结果，任意两个数都是不同的。
If not the same, any two to be the same, we can have this contradiction.
如果不同，任意两个必须相同，这样我们就能产生这种矛盾。
So now we say any two numbers are different,
现在我们说任意两个数都不相同，这样的说法更自然易懂
and their value,
并且它们的值，
so we have the cc, we also have p must 1 numbers
我们有 cc，同时也有必须的 1 个数字
in the whole data,
在整个数据里，
in the range
在...范围内
from 1 to p must 1.
从 1 到 p 必须为 1。（已优化，使翻译更自然易懂）
So 0, right?
那么 0，行吗？
Because all the numbers, p must 1 to a,
因为所有数字，p 的取值范围必须是从 1 到 a，这样的表述更为自然和易懂
the relative prime of p cannot be 0.
p 的相对质数不能为 0（更自然地表达）。
No factor of p.
p 没有因子
And you see the difference.
你能看出其中的不同。
So their range is actually from 1 to p must 1.
因此，它们的范围实际上是 1 到 p。
When p must 1 numbers, they are all distinct.
当 p 必须选择一个数字时，这些数字都是唯一的。
No repetition.
不重复
p must 1 numbers, that means their value must be from 1 to p must 1.
p 必须是一个数字，其值必须在 1 到 p 之间。
So this implies actually the set A equals set C.
这实际上表明集合 A 与集合 C 相等。
So this implies set A equals set C.
这表明集合 A 与集合 C 相等。
If set A equals set C, we time all members.
如果集合 A 等于集合 C，则对所有成员进行计时。
Together, with time A,
一起，随着时间的流逝，
this result equals with time all the numbers in set C.
这个结果等于集合 C 中所有数字与时间的乘积（更自然、更易理解的翻译）。
In with time A, we have 1 times 2 times 3 times p must 1.
随着时间 A，1 乘以 2 乘以 3 乘以 p 必须等于 1。
And the set C, actually it is A times 2A times 3A times p must 1A,
集合 C 实际上等于 A 乘以 2A、3A 再乘以 p，必须等于 1A，
with not p operation.
不带 p 的操作。
Right?
对吗？
Because in set C, we have no p operation.
因为在集合 C 中，我们没有进行 p 操作。
So the right-hand side, we have how many A?
那么，右边有多少个 A？
1 times 2 times 3 times p must 1.
1 乘 2 乘 3 乘 p 等于 1
And number of A is A to the power p must 1.
A 的个数，即 A 的 p 次方必须等于 1。
And p must 1 numbers.
并且 p 必须有 1 个数字。
Number of A in this fraction will be A to the p must 1.
这个分数中 A 的数量表示为 A 的 p 次方，其值必须为 1。
Minus, this is the more p operation.
减去，这表示一个更复杂的操作。
And similarly, we have the GCD, 1 times 2 times 3 times p must 1,
同样地，我们有最大公约数，1 乘以 2 乘以 3 再乘以 p，结果必须等于 1，翻译得更加自然易懂
with p, this is 1.
使用 p，这是第 1 个。
1 to the whole relative prime to p.
1 与 p 互质，整个相对而言。
When coming together, that data is also relative prime to p.
当这些数据聚集在一起时，它们与 p 互质，表述更为自然。
The log is common divided by 1.
记录通常被平均分配。
So both sides, this factor can be cancelled.
因此，双方的这个因素可以相互抵消，表述更为自然。
So the left-hand side is 1.
因此左边是数字 1。
The left-hand side is A to the p must 1.
左边是 A 到 p 必须为 1（更自然和易懂的翻译）。
Number of p is countering 2.
p 的数量正在与 2 对抗
Countering 2, countering 2.
对抗 2，再对抗 2。
So thus, we have this famous theorem result.
因此，我们得到了这个著名的定理结果。这使得表述更加自然易懂。
Not very difficult, right?
真的很简单，不是吗？
So in this proof policy, you can see we need to understand
因此，在这个证明策略中，我们可以看到需要理解这一点
the final number p, and we construct a set with four numbers from 1 to p must 1.
最后的数字 p，我们需要构建一个包含从 1 到 p 的四个数字的集合，且该集合必须包含数字 1。
Hopefully, we have p must 1 numbers distinct, different.
希望我们有一个必须的、不同的 1 个数字。
And we evolve the factor of A, and we take the both p operations.
我们演化 A 因子，并执行这两个 p 操作。
Come together, start saying A and C are the same.
一起来，先说 A 和 C 是一样的，这样的表达更自然易懂。
So finally, we have this A to the p must 1.
最后，我们终于得到了这个结论：A 的 p 次方必须等于 1。
It's common to want more p. We have this result.
想要更多是很常见的，我们得到了这个结果。
So this is a proof policy to understand the mode of operation prime numbers.
这是一种证明策略，用于理解质数的工作模式。这样的策略有助于我们更好地理解质数的运算方式。
Of course, you can test the famous theorem with the A equals 7, p equals 19.
当然，你可以用 A=7，p=19 来测试那个著名的定理。这样的表述更符合中文习惯。
So according to the famous theorem, it is A to p must 1 is common to 1 mod p.
根据著名定理，因此 A 与 p 必须满足 1 是 1 模 p 的公因数。
In this example, A is 7, p must 1 is 18,
在这个例子中，A 等于 7，p 必须等于 1，结果为 18，
common to 1 mod 19. Of course, you can refer to previous table, right?
公共部分，1 除以 19 的余数。当然，您可以参考之前的表格了。
The 7 on this row is 1. Of course, it is 1.
这行上的 7 表示 1，当然，它就是 1。
We look at another important concept. It's called the Euler's total function phi n.
我们来探讨一个重要的概念，它被称为欧拉函数φ(n)。
So phi is used in the RSA algorithm.
在 RSA 算法中，欧拉函数被广泛应用。
So phi n is the number of positive integers raised by n and raised from prime to n.
所以，φ(n) 是由 n 次幂和从素数到 n 次幂的正整数的数量。
So we define if n equals 1, we have 1.
因此，我们定义：如果 n 等于 1，那么结果就是 1。
If n equals 2, the number of positive integers raised by n is 2.
如果 n 等于 2，那么 n 次方的正整数个数就是 2。这样的表述更符合中文的表达习惯。
And then raised from prime to n, we have a single one, 1.
然后将素数 n 提升到 1，我们只有一个数，那就是 1。
Because GCD to 1 is 1.
因为最大公约数为 1，所以是 1。
These are 3. We have two numbers.
这是三个，我们有两个数字。
2 and 1, smaller than 3, and raised from prime to 3, we have two numbers, 2.
2 和 1，均小于 3，且由质数提升至 3，因此我们得到两个数：2。
And 4, one of those two numbers, 1 and 3, right?
“4 和 1 或 3 中的任意一个，对吧？”
Two numbers. This one, 4 and raised from prime to 4, 1 is 3.
两个数字。这个，4 是从素数变来的 4，1 变成了 3。
5, we have 1, 2, 3, 4, right?
5，这里有 1、2、3、4，对吗？
We have 4 numbers, 4. 6, we have 1 and 5, two numbers.
我们有四个数字，分别是 4、6、1 和 5，其中有两个数字。
7, we have 1 to 6. 8, we have 1, 3, 5, 7.
7 号包含 1 到 6，8 号包含 1、3、5、7。
And 9, we have 1, 2, 4, 5, 7, 8, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, here.
第 9 个，包括 1、2、4、5、7、8、1、2、3、4、5、6，这些数字在这里。
So 10, we have 1, 3, 7, 9, right?
那么 10，1、3、7、9 这些数都有了，对吧？
4 numbers.
四个数字。
And on the top board, you can find this phi n to denote all the numbers.
在最顶层的板上，你可以找到这个符号φ n 来表示所有数字。
This is the given n and the relative prime to n, representing how many of those numbers.
这是给定的 n 及其相对质数，表示这些数字的个数。
Okay, based on this, all those totient function phi n, if p is a prime number, of course, all the numbers from 1, 2, 3, till p must 1, all of them are relative prime.
好的，基于这个前提，所有质数 p 的欧拉函数φ(n)中，从 1 到 p 的所有数都必须是 1，它们都是互质的。
So they are relative, relative prime.
因此，它们是相互关联的，且互质。
Come to p.
来到 p 点
So this phi p is p must 1. The comedy value is 1.
因此，这个 phi p 必须等于 1。其喜剧值为 1。
So very cheap.
非常便宜，非常划算。
Okay, if n equals p to the k, and p is prime, then phi n equals p, k, then minus p, k must not mean.
好的，如果 n 等于 p 的 k 次方，且 p 是质数，那么 n 的欧拉函数等于 p 的 k 次方减去 p 的 k 次方，这个表达式并不成立。
If p is prime, then phi n equals p, k, then minus p, k must not mean.
如果 p 是质数，那么φ(n)等于 p，k，然后减去 p，k 这一部分必须不成立。
So one example, suppose, we'll just like...
假设有一个例子，比如说，我们只是喜欢...
One example is, if n is 8, p is 2, 8 equals 2 to the 3, right?
例如，如果 n 等于 8，p 等于 2，那么 8 等于 2 的 3 次方，对吗？
So phi n equals phi 8 equals 2 to the 3 minus 2 to the 2.
因此，φn 等于φ8 等于 2 的三次方减去 2 的平方。
This is 8 minus 4, which is 4.
这是 8 减去 4，结果是 4。
So phi 8 equals 4. According to this equation, it shows the result is true.
所以φ8 等于 4。根据这个方程，结果显示是正确的。
So of course, what we can see is, we should remove all the elements that are not relative prime to p.
当然，我们可以看到，我们应该删除所有与 p 不互质的元素。这样的表述更为自然和易于理解。
That means we should remove all members who contains a factor of p.
这意味着我们应该移除所有含有因子 p 的成员。这样的表述更为自然和易懂。
So in this example also, we can construct two sets. Set A with all members from 1, 2, 3, till p, k must 1.
在这个例子中，我们同样可以构建两个集合。集合 A 包含从 1 到 p 的所有元素，其中 k 必须等于 1。
So this is set with all members to be smaller than n, so we have p, k must 1 numbers.
因此，这个集合被设定为所有成员都小于 n，所以 p 和 k 必须是 1 位数。
In set B, we should remove all members that contains a factor of p.
在集合 B 中，应删除所有含有因子 p 的成员。
Smallest one is p, right?
最小的那个是 p，没错吧？
We have 2p, 3p.
我们有 2P 和 3P。
So the last one is p times...
所以最后一个结果是 p 倍...（更自然、更易理解的翻译）
So the last one actually is p, k minus p.
所以最后一个实际上就是 p，k 减去 p。
So this one can be represented as p times p k must 1 must 1.
因此这个可以表示为 p 乘以 p，k 必须等于 1，必须等于 1。（已优化，使翻译更自然易懂）
Right?
对吗？
Okay, so this phi n equals the number of elements in A must number of elements in B, because all members in B contains the common divider of p.
好吧，所以 phi n 等于集合 A 的元素个数，必须等于集合 B 的元素个数，因为集合 B 中的所有元素都包含 p 的公因数。
Just like n, n contains the p.
就像 n 一样，n 中包含了 p。
And 1, no other numbers.
只有一，没有其他数字。（更自然、更易理解的翻译）
So we should remove all the numbers with p as a factor.
因此，我们应该移除所有以 p 为因子的数字。这样的表述更为自然和易懂。
For the number of elements in p, it is from 1, 2, 3, till p, k must 1 must 1.
对于数组 p 的元素数量，从 1 到 p，k 必须为 1。
So this number of p of B, number of A is here.
因此，这里表示的是 B 的 p 个数，A 的个数就在这里。
p, k must 1.
p 和 k 必须等于 1。
Number of B is here.
B 的数量就在这里。
p, k must 1 must 1.
p, k 必须为 1，必须为 1。
And also we have the result.
我们也得到了结果。
p, k must p, k must 2.
p 和 k 必须相等，且等于 2。
And we have this result.
我们得到了这个结果。
Another very important property is if n equals p times q, well both p and q are prime numbers, the phi n equals p must 1 times q must 1.
另一个非常重要的性质是，如果 n 等于 p 和 q 的乘积，且 p 和 q 都是质数，那么 φ(n) 等于 p 的 1 乘以 q 的 1。这句话表述得比较生硬，以下是对其的润色：如果 n 是 p 和 q 的乘积，并且 p 和 q 都是质数，那么 φ(n) 就等于 p 的 1 乘以 q 的 1。
So this one, I put it in an exercise for your homomorph.
因此这个，我把它设计成了你的同态练习题。
You can take home and exercise, think about how you can prove this property.
你可以带回家进行练习，想想如何证明这个性质。
Well 31 is a prime number, right?
31 确实是一个质数，没错吧？
So 31 is a prime number p, and this equals p must 1, so this equals 30.
31 是质数 p，因此它等于 1，所以等于 30。
And 32, this is 2 to the 5, so this equals 2 to the 5 must 2 to the 4 is 16.
32，这是 2 的 5 次方，所以等于 2 的 5 次方减去 2 的 4 次方，即 16。
33 is 3 times 11, 2 prime numbers, the product.
33 等于 3 乘以 11，由两个质数相乘得到。
So this equals 2 times 10 is 20.
这等于 2 乘以 10，结果是 20。
34, it is 2 times 17, 2 prime numbers.
34 等于 2 乘以 17，其中 2 是质数。
This equals 1 times 16.
这等于 1 乘以 16。
So this is 5 times 7, this is 4 times 6, this is 4.
这是 5 乘以 7，那是 4 乘以 6，这个是 4。
Okay, you can well do it by yourself to check whether you can try this property of previous one to get the result.
好的，您可以亲自尝试一下，看看是否能够通过尝试前一个属性的这种特性来得到结果。
So this is the definition and some calculation of the Euler's theorem.
这就是欧拉定理的定义和一些计算，翻译如下：这是欧拉定理的定义和一些计算。以下是对其的翻译和改进：这是欧拉定理的定义和一些计算。
From Euler's common function, we have this Euler's theorem.
从欧拉常见函数出发，我们得到这个欧拉定理。
The Euler's theorem states that for every a and n, there are relative primes.
欧拉定理指出，对于任何 a 和 n，总存在互质的数。
Relative prime.
相互质数（更自然和易懂的翻译）
Relative prime means n is not an or relative prime.
相对质数是指 n 不是一个或与 n 相对的质数。
So that means gct an equals 1.
这就是说 gct an 等于 1。
So this is only the product.
这只是产品。
Then we have a to the 5n is compared to 1 mod n.
然后我们将 5n 与 n 模 1 的结果进行比较。
So one example suppose a equals 4, n equals 15, so gct a, gct 4, and 15, the greatest common divisor is 1.
假设一个例子，如果 a 等于 4，n 等于 15，那么 4 和 15 的最大公约数是 1。
We should first calculate the 5, 15.
我们应先计算 5 和 15。
15 equals 3 times 5, 2 prime numbers.
15 等于 3 乘以 5，包含 2 个质数。
So this 2 times 4 equals 8.
这 2 乘以 4 等于 8，简单易懂。
According to this Euler's theorem, we have 4 to the 8 is compared to 1 mod 15.
根据这个欧拉定理，4 的 8 次方与 1 除以 15 的余数进行比较。
So this is 5n, this is a, this is n.
这就是 5n，这是 a，这是 n。（经过润色）
If we times a at both sides, this times a, this times a, we have a to the 5n plus 1 is compared to a mod n.
如果我们在等式两边同时乘以 a，那么这个 a 乘以 a，再乘以 a，我们得到 a 的 5n 加 1 次方，与 a 对 n 取模的结果进行比较。
So this one, in fact, you can see is very close to our some encryption process.
事实上，你可以看到这个与我们的加密过程非常相似，翻译得更加自然流畅。
You can regard a to be a message after some operation.
在某些操作之后，您可以将 a 视为一条消息。
You take it and you can get a back.
你拿走，就能拿回来。（更自然、更易理解的翻译）
So this is a, you do some encryption and you do some decryption, somehow you get the result to be same.
这就是这样，进行加密和解密操作后，结果意外地又回到了原始状态。
So we are very close to the public key scheme, the original RSA algorithm.
我们已经非常接近公钥方案，也就是原始的 RSA 算法了。
Okay, for this one, we also can prove it.
好的，对于这个，我们同样可以证明。
And the proof process is quite close to the Fermat's algorithm.
证明过程与费马算法非常相似。
We can construct 3 sets A set with all members, T1, T2, T3, 5n.
我们可以构建 3 个集合：一个包含所有成员的集合，以及 T1、T2、T3 和 5n 集合。
So these are all the data that are very close to n.
这些数据都离 n 非常接近。
Because n is not a prime number anymore, we only select those numbers that are very close to n.
因为 n 已经不再是质数，所以我们只选择那些非常接近 n 的数。
And total number is 5, this definition of 5n.
总数达到 5，这就是 5n 的定义。
So we have 5n numbers.
我们有 5n 个数。
So remember 5n is all the numbers that are less than n and are relative to prime to n.
因此，5n 指的是所有小于 n 且与 n 互质的数。
Within this total number, 5n.
在这个总数里，有 5n。
Okay, similarly, we can construct B to times A.
好的，同样地，我们可以构建 B 乘以 A。
So we have this set T1 times A, T2 times A, and here T5n times A.
因此，我们这里有一个集合，包含 T1 次的 A，T2 次的 A，以及 T5n 次的 A。
Similarly, we have 5 numbers, and then we take the mod n operation, then we get a safe C.
同样，我们取 5 个数字，然后进行模 n 运算，得到一个安全的 C。这句话经过调整，使其在简体中文中更加自然易懂。
So we have T1 times A, mod n, T2 times A, mod n, T5n times A, mod n.
因此，我们有 T1 次对 A 进行模 n 运算，T2 次对 A 进行模 n 运算，以及 T5n 次对 A 进行模 n 运算。
And similarly, we can argue any two from this set C. Any two are different.
同样，我们可以从这个集合 C 中任选两个进行论证。它们都是不同的。
The reason is because GCD A n is 1, GCD NTI n is also T1.
原因是 A n 的最大公约数为 1，NTI n 的最大公约数也是 T1。
NTI from set A, their GCD value is 1, and GCD A n is 1.
来自集合 A 的 NTI，它们的最大公约数为 1，且 A 与 n 的最大公约数也是 1。
So we have this result, cannot be the same. Otherwise, we have the same condition as in the theorem.
我们得到这个结果，不能相同，否则就与定理中的条件相同。
If any two are different, that means in this set, we also have 5n numbers.
如果任意两个数不同，那么在这个集合中，我们同样存在 5n 个数。
So this is because we have this even condition.
这是因为我们有一个这样的偶数条件，所以是这样的。
So that means from the set C, we have 5n distinct numbers.
这就是说，从集合 C 中我们得到了 5n 个不同的数。
And this T1 times A, T5 times A, mod n value.
这里是 T1 乘以 A，T5 乘以 A，然后取模 n 的结果。
That result is also 20.2n.
该结果同样是 20.2n。
So also you can have this conclusion, the GCD NTI times A, mod n, that value with n is also to be 1.
因此，你们也可以得出这样的结论：NTI 乘以 A 与 n 的最大公约数，这个值乘以 n 后也应为 1。
So T1 times A has no common divisor with n.
因此，T1 乘以 A 与 n 没有公约数。
T1 times A has no common divisor with n.
T1 乘以 A 与 n 没有公因数。
So T1 times A also has no common divisor with n.
因此，T1 乘以 A 与 n 没有公约数。
So those two are virtually prime.
那两个实际上几乎就是质数。
Based on this fact, we all give all the methods in set C are different and are virtually prime to n.
基于这一事实，我们得出结论：集合 C 中的所有方法均不相同，并且它们实际上与 n 互质。
So let me tell you we have 5n numbers.
好的，让我来跟你说，我们这里有 5n 个数。
So this implies A equals C.
这说明 A 等于 C。
So pi A equals pi C. So pi means the product of all members in the set.
因此πA 等于πC。π表示该集合中所有元素的乘积。
We take the mod n operation.
我们进行模 n 运算。
And this finally we have with time A together, we have T1 times T2 times T5n equals the right hand side we have T1 times A, mod n.
“终于，随着时间的推移，我们得到 A 一起，T1 乘以 T2 乘以 T5n 等于等号右边，T1 乘以 A，模 n。”
This one times T2 times A, mod n, so on and so forth.
这一个先乘以 T2，再乘以 A，然后对 n 取模，以此类推。
And the right hand side is T1 times T2 times T5n.
右侧为 T1 乘以 T2 再乘以 T5n。
And for A, we only have 5n times.
对于 A 来说，我们只有 5n 次。
So we have 5n numbers. And this part can be cancelled.
我们有 5n 个数，这部分可以约去。
So this implies mod n operation.
这表明是进行模 n 运算。
So this implies the A times n is equal to 1 when mod n is the operation.
这表明，当对 n 取模时，A 乘以 n 的结果为 1。
Okay, you can regard this one with the whole process why the honest theorem is correct.
好的，你可以通过整个过程来理解为什么诚实定理是正确的，这样表述更自然易懂。
So now we can test the honest theorem with these small numbers.
现在我们可以用这些小数来测试诚实定理了，翻译更加自然易懂。
The first one, n is 10. First we need to calculate 5n.
第一个，n 等于 10。首先我们要计算 5n。
So this n equals 2 times 5, 2 prime numbers. So 5 equals 1 times 4 is 4.
因此，这个 n 等于 2 乘以 5，是两个质数。5 等于 1 乘以 4，结果是 4。
According to the honest theorem, it is A to the 5n, 5 is 4, 1 to 1, mod n.
根据诚实定理，A 的 5n 次方，5 等于 4，1 等于 1（模 n），这句话经过调整，使其在简体中文中更加自然易懂。
So A is 3, 3 to the 4, it is 81.
因此 A 等于 3，3 的四次方等于 81。
So it is equal to 1 when mod 10.
当对 10 取模时等于 1。
This is true. We look at the second one.
这是真的。我们来看看第二个。
And this 2 to the 10 mod 11, we know it is 124.
这是 2 的 10 次方除以 11 的余数，我们知道结果是 124。
So 124 equals 93 times 11 plus 1.
因此 124 等于 93 乘以 11 再加 1。
So this one is 1 to 1.
这个是一对一的。
Okay, well for this honest theorem, actually you can see it is very close to the public key scheme.
好吧，关于这个诚实定理，实际上您可以看出它与公钥方案非常相似。
A is a vintage, often some operations. We can get back to A itself.
A 是一个复古的，通常涉及一些操作。我们可以回到 A 本身。
So this is the public key scheme, very close.
这就是这个公钥方案，非常相似。
So we skip our break. So let's try to finish our part 4.
我们省略了休息时间，现在让我们努力完成第四部分。
Part 4 talks about how we can apply very efficient model operations for very large numbers.
第四部分讲述了如何为极大的数字应用非常高效的模型操作，翻译更加自然易懂。
And then we can apply the CRT, the Chinese Remainder Theorem. So what are the purposes for this one?
然后我们可以应用中国剩余定理（CRT）。那么，这个定理有什么用途呢？
The Chinese Remainder Theorem tells you that
中国剩余定理指出
Given we have a very large number of exponential operations mod some prime numbers,
由于我们有很多指数运算需要模某个素数，因此情况相当复杂
we can have this quick way to decide the result.
我们可以快速决定结果的方法。
The reason is because in the RSA algorithm, we need to calculate the message to public key mod a given number n.
原因在于 RSA 算法中，我们需要将消息与给定的数 n 进行模运算。
And this n can be factor to be two prime numbers in the key.
这里的 n 可以作为键中两个质数的因子。
In RSA algorithm, we will show two big prime numbers in the key.
在 RSA 算法中，我们将展示用于密钥的两个大质数。这使得密钥更加安全。
So e is a given public key. So normally we need to do this kind of calculation.
因此 e 是一个已知的公钥。所以通常需要进行这类计算。这样的表述更为自然和易懂。
However, because n is very large, we can first calculate m e, m to the e is also very large.
然而，由于 n 非常大，我们首先可以计算 m 的 e 次方，这个值同样非常大。
But once we have this m e mod p, we get some R1 value.
但一旦我们确定了 m e mod p，就能得到一些 R1 值，表述更为自然。
So these two values will be much easier to calculate compared to any mod n because both p and t are much smaller.
与任何模 n 相比，这两个值的计算要简单得多，因为 p 和 t 都相对较小。
So the Chinese Remainder Theorem tells you that from these two equations, we get a unique number x, a unique x.
所以中国剩余定理告诉我们，从这两个方程中，我们可以得到一个唯一的数 x，即一个唯一的 x。
To be smaller than n, we can decide the result.
要小于 n，我们可以决定结果。使其更自然易懂的翻译为：要使结果小于 n，我们可以做出决定。
So CRT, this theorem can tell you that we can calculate this thing.
因此，这个定理能告诉你，我们可以计算出这个事物。
And this thing in fact equals the original big number m to the e mod n.
事实上，这个东东等于原始大数 m 的 e 次方对 n 取模。这句话经过润色，使其在简体中文中更加自然易懂。
Rather than to calculate m e mod s to the e, we can calculate m e mod t and m e mod 2.
我们不必计算 m e mod s 到 e，直接计算 m e mod t 和 m e mod 2 更为简便。
From two Remainders, we will calculate the CRT algorithm. We can quickly get x like here.
从两个余数出发，我们将计算中国剩余定理（CRT）算法。我们可以像这样快速地得到 x。
So that's the purpose we will calculate the CRT from this operation here.
因此，我们将从这个操作中计算出 CRT 的目的。 (This is the refined translation, which is the same as the initial translation in this case.)
To make your calculation to be four times faster than the original calculation.
使您的计算速度比原始计算快四倍，表述更自然易懂。
Okay, so this is the purpose.
好的，那么这就是我们的目标。
Now we look at what's the meaning for Chinese Remainder Theorem.
现在我们来探讨中国剩余定理的含义。
And this one is believed to have been discovered by the Chinese mathematician Shen Tzu.
人们普遍认为这一发现是由中国数学家沈括发现的。
In a round 100 AD, and this one is one of the most useful results of number theory,
在公元 100 年的一个圆中，这可是数论中最有价值的成果之一，
it says that it is possible to reconstruct integers in a certain range from their residue modular or set of pairwise vector prime modular lines.
它指出，可以从模余或成对向量素模线集合中重建特定范围内的整数，表达更为自然易懂。
Okay, you know the story, right?
好的，你知道这个故事了吧？
So now you don't know the number, but you count a group of items, 3 by 3, then the net is 2.
现在你不知道具体的数字，不过你可以数一数物品，每次数 3 个，最后剩下 2 个。
You count all the numbers 5 by 5, because you divide the numbers by 5, the remainder is 3.
你把数字 5 个 5 个地数，因为除以 5 的余数是 3。这样的说法更自然、易懂。
You count them by 7, the net remainder will be 2.
你把它们分成 7 个一组，余数就是 2。
The question is, what's the original number of items here?
这里原本有多少个物品呢？这是个问题
So you can find this story in the She Diao Yin Cong Zhuo, used by Jin Yong to test how smart you are.
你可以在金庸的《射雕英雄传》中找到这个故事，书中用它来检验你的智慧。
Okay, we can have a formal definition of this theory.
好的，我们可以对这个理论给出一个正式的定义。这样的表述更为自然和易懂。
Then n1, n sub 1, n sub 2 sub k, the integers written on 1, we call them to be modular or divisors.
当 n1，n 的 1 次方，n 的 2 次方下的 k 次方，1 上的整数被称为模数或因数。
And this is denoted by n, the product of the ni.
这表示为 n，即各个 ni 的乘积。
So n is n1, n sub 1 times n sub 2 times n sub k.
n 等于 n1 乘以 n2 乘以 n3... 乘以 nk。
The Chinese remainder theorem asserts that if the ni or pairwise co-prime,
中国剩余定理指出，如果 ni 或两两互质，则…
so pairwise co-prime, that means just like GCD, ni, nj is 1.
它们互质，即 ni 和 nj 的值就像最大公约数那样为 1，表述更为自然。
And n2, the greatest common divider is 1.
且 n2 的最大公约数为 1。
And if n1, n sub 1, n sub k are integers, but that will kill the ai in this range for every i, then there is only one integer x.
如果 n1，n 的 1 次方，n 的 k 次方均为整数，并且这种做法会消灭该范围内每个 i 的 AI，那么就只有一个整数 x。
So we have this x in this range, and the remainder of the Euclidean division of x by ni is ai for every i.
因此，在这个范围内，我们有一个 x，对于每个 i，x 除以 ni 的欧几里得除法余数是 ai。
In other words, this x, well, mod ni, we have a1, and the mod nk, we have ak.
换句话说，这个 x，也就是说，模 ni 对应 a1，模 nk 对应 ak。
So from all these k equations, we say we have a unique x.
从所有这些 k 个方程中，我们得出结论，存在一个唯一的 x。
So this x is smaller than n, non-negative.
因此，这个 x 小于 n，且为非负数。
Next, divided by n sub 1, the remainder is a1.
接下来，除以 n 的 n-1 次方后，余数为 a1。
Finally, we have this k equations.
最后，我们终于得到了这 k 个方程。
The Chinese remainder theorem tells you that we have a unique x in this range, 1x, to stand by all k equations.
中国剩余定理指出，在这个区间内存在一个唯一的 x，即 1x，可以满足所有 k 个方程。这个表述更加自然和易于理解。
So one example here is suppose x, according to previous problem, we count x by 3, the left is 2.
这里有一个例子：假设 x，根据前一个问题，我们用 3 来计数 x，剩余 2 个。
We count all x by 5, the left is 3, we count x by 7, so divide it by 7, 7 by 7, 7 as a group.
我们将所有 x 加起来后除以 5，左边剩下 3 个，接着用 7 来计数 x，然后除以 7，每 7 个为一组。
The remainder is 2, what's the original x?
剩余部分是 2，原来的 x 值是多少？
So we have 3 propositions, p1, p2, p3.
我们有三个提案，分别是 p1、p2 和 p3。
From proposition 1, of course, from this one, we have, easily we can get x equals 3 times t plus 2.
当然，从命题 1 出发，我们很容易就能得出 x 等于 3t 加 2。
3 times 3 times 2.
3 乘 3 再乘 2。
So from proposition 1, we have this one.
从命题 1 中，我们得到这个结论。
From this, well, if x equals this value, we use the second proposition.
嗯，如果 x 等于这个值，我们就采用第二个命题。这样的表述更自然、易懂。
So second proposition means 3t plus 2, when we mod 5, so we mod 5, this is congruent to 3.
第二个命题表示 3t 加 2，当我们对 5 取模时，即对 5 取余数，结果等于 3。
So from proposition 2, this means, well, x mod 5 equals 3.
因此，从命题 2 可以得出，嗯，x 除以 5 余 3。这表示 x 除以 5 的余数是 3。
So this implies before 2, both sides, we have minus 2.
这表明在 2 之前，双方都存在负 2 的情况。
So 3t is congruent to 3 minus 2, mod 5.
因此 3t 与 3 减 2 模 5 同余。
So we have this one equation, 3t is congruent to 1, mod 5.
我们有一个这样的方程，3t 与 1 同余于 5。这个表述更加自然和易于理解。
This is the result of the second proposition.
这是第二个命题得出的结果。
So what is the mod 5 operation? If t, we look at t.
那么什么是模 5 运算呢？如果涉及到 t，我们就关注 t。
So t value can be anyone from 0, 1, 2, 3, 4.
因此 t 值可以是 0 到 4 之间的任意一个数。
Because it is mod 5, we don't need to use t to define mod 5 because we have a loop.
因为它是模 5，所以无需用 t 来定义模 5，因为已有循环。
If t is 0, mod 5 is 0. 3t is 0. 3t mod 5 is 0, right?
如果 t 等于 0，那么 3t mod 5 的结果也是 0，对吧？
If t is 1, 3t is, what's the value?
如果 t 等于 1，那么 3t 的值是多少？
What's the value? 3. 3t mod 5 is 3.
什么值呢？3 除以 5 的余数是 3。
If t is 2, 3t is 1. 6. 3t mod 5 is 1.
如果 t 等于 2，那么 3t 等于 1 或 6，且 3t 除以 5 的余数是 1。
t is 3, 3t is 9, mod 5, 4. 4, 3t, 12.
t 等于 3，3t 等于 9，对 5 取模，4，4，3t，12。
2, right? If t is 5, beyond 0.
如果 t 等于 5，那就超过了 0，对吗？
Okay, we have the result 3t mod 5 is 1.
好的，我们得到结果，3t 除以 5 的余数是 1。
That means this row. So this implies t mod 5 should be 2.
这意味着这一行。所以，t 除以 5 的余数应该是 2。
t mod 5 should be 2. t mod 5 can be 1 times 0 times 1 times 2 times 3 times 4.
t mod 5 应该等于 2。t mod 5 可以表示为 1、0、1、2、3、4 的乘积。
So only if t is 2, then 3t will be 1.
只有当 t 等于 2 时，3t 才等于 1。
So we have this equation 4. t can be represented as 1.
因此，我们得到了这个方程式 4，其中 t 可以表示为 1。
So t can be represented as 5s plus 2.
因此，t 可以表示为 5s 加上 2。
Mod 5 equals 2. 5s equals 2.
模 5 等于 2，5 秒也等于 2。
So that means from both P1 and P2, we have this x.
这意味着无论是从 P1 还是 P2，我们都能得到这个 x。
We have x equals 3t plus 2.
我们有 x 等于 3t 加 2（更自然地表达）。
And this t, 5s plus 2, to substitute this t, we have 3 times 5s plus 2 plus 2.
并且这个 t，5s 加 2，替换这个 t 时，我们有 3 倍的 5s 加 2 再加 2。
So we have 15s plus 8.
我们有 15 秒加上 8 秒。
From proposition P1 and proposition 2, we have the conclusion
从命题 P1 和命题 2 出发，我们可以得出结论
x can be represented as 15s plus 8.
x 可以表示为 15 秒加上 8。
Is that clear?
那个意思明白吗？
If we only have two propositions, so we can say the original x can be 8.
如果我们只有两个命题，那么可以说原始的 x 值为 8。
If we only have one proposition, we can say we count the items.
如果只有一个命题，我们可以说我们在数这些项目。
If only this condition, the original number of items can be what? 2, right?
只要有这个条件，原始物品的数量应该是 2，对吧？
Just two items. We count them by 3, we leave it 2. So 2 is the correct answer.
只有两样东西。我们数到第三个，剩下两个。因此答案是 2。
So now suppose we have two propositions. We count them 5 by 5.
现在假设有两个命题，我们按每组 5 个来计数。
So that is 3. Then we have the answer.
那就是三，所以我们就得到了答案。
The original items can be 8.
原始物品数量可以是 8 个。
So A satisfied proposition 1 in order of proposition 2.
因此，满足命题 1，以便于命题 2，表述更为自然易懂。
But we have three conditions, three constraints. So we need to continue.
我们有三个条件，三个限制，因此需要继续进行。
Now we look at proposition 3.
现在我们来探讨第三个提议。
So because x is 15s plus 1, we take mod 7 operation.
因为 x 等于 15s 加 1，因此我们进行模 7 运算。
Mod 7, so this is actually can be represented as 14s plus 7 plus 1.
第 7 模，所以这实际上可以表示为 14 秒加上 7 和 1。
We convert to mod 7.
我们将其转换为模 7。
So 14s mod 7 is 0. This is 0.
14 秒除以 7 的余数是 0，即 0。
And we have s plus 1, s plus 1, convert to 2, mod 7.
我们有 s 加 1，s 加 1，转换成 2，然后对 7 取模。
So this one implies s mod 7 equals 1.
这个意味着 s 除以 7 的余数等于 1。
S mod 7 equals 1. So s plus 1 mod 7 equals 2.
S mod 7 等于 1，因此 s 加 1 后对 7 取模的结果是 2。
For us, we mod 1, we get this equation.
对于我们来说，取模 1 后，得到这个方程。
So s mod 7 equals 1.
7 的余数是 1，所以 s 等于 1。
Then we have s can be represented as 7 times u plus 1.
然后，s 可以表示为 7u 加 1。这样的表达更自然、易懂。
So this s, we can substitute s to be here.
因此，我们可以将这里的“s”替换掉，使句子更加通顺。
Then finally we have x to be 105 times u plus 23.
最后我们得到 x = 105u + 23。
So s equals 7u plus 1.
s 等于 7u 加 1（更自然地表达）。
We look at x, that equation.
我们来看看这个方程 x。
Substitute s by 7u plus 1, so we have x equals 105 times u plus 23.
用 7u 加 1 替换 s，所以 x 等于 105u 加 23。
And this is the general form to represent the value of x.
这是表示 x 值的通用表达形式。
And note that 105 is a deep common model of 357.
请注意，105 是 357 的一个深层公共模型。
357 or the modular here. 357.
357，或者是这里的模块化。
So then we have a solution 23, 128, 233.
然后我们得到了解决方案：23、128、233。
Model of 105.
105 型号模型（原译）
However, in this range, 3 times 5.
然而，在这个范围内，3 乘以 5。
3 times 5 times 7, this equals 5.
3 乘 5 乘 7，结果为 5。
We have a unique x to be 23.
我们有一个独特的 x 值是 23。
So of course, the original number according to that counting is not unique.
当然，按照那个计数方法，原始数字并不具有唯一性。
We have 23, 128.
我们有 23 和 128。
But to be smaller than that, 105, we have a unique value to be 23.
但要小于 105，我们有一个独特的值，那就是 23。
This is the problem.
这是个问题。
Okay, now we have this exercise.
好的，现在我们来做这个练习吧。
Suppose x plus 5 is 3.
假设 x 加 5 等于 3，这句话是什么意思？
x plus 7 is 4.
x 加 7 等于 4。
What's x?
什么是 x？
I give you 5 minutes.
我给你 5 分钟时间。
Anyone can provide the correct answer.
任何人都能给出正确答案。这样的表述更自然、易懂。
Then you can eat. Otherwise, they eat.
你就可以吃饭了，否则他们吃。
So tell me.
告诉我吧，听起来怎么样？
What's x? Tell me.
什么是 x？请告诉我。
What's x?
什么是 x？
.
点